Guide to the Payne Whitney Gymnasium, Yale University, Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Payne Whitney Gymnasium, Yale University, photographs
1930-1968
RU 612
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
The materials consist of photographs documenting the construction of Payne Whitney Gymnasium at Yale. Included are exterior and interior views, specifically photographs of the trophy and exercise rooms, pools, squash courts, and the indoor track.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-B (YRG 46-B), Records and materials documenting individual Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged in two series: I. Construction Progress Photographs, 1930-1932. II. General Views, 1930-1968.
Scope and Contents
The materials consist of photographs documenting the construction of Payne Whitney Gymnasium at Yale. Included are exterior and interior views, specifically photographs of the trophy and exercise rooms, pools, squash courts, and the indoor track.
College buildings -- Design and construction; Slides (photographs); Photographs; Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings
- Construction progress photographs, 1930-1932; Series I
  - 1930 June: site, pre-construction (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1930 Aug-Sept: excavation (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1930 Oct-Nov: foundation (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1930 Dec-1931 Jan (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1931 Feb-Mar (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1931 Apr-May (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 1931 Jun-Jul (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 1931 Aug-Sep (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1931 Oct-Nov (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1931 Dec-1932 Jan (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition & practice pools, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sculpture models
    - Cornices (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Shields, natural forms (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Statues (Box 1, Folder 14)
- General views, circa 1930-1968; Series II
  - Construction views (Box 2, Folder 1 - 2)
  - Exterior, 1932-1960s, undated (Box 2, Folder 3 - 5)
  - Chamberlain etching, 1933-1934 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Outdoor track, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Interior
    - General, 1968, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Exercise rooms, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Gymnastics room, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Pool, 1959, 1968, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Steam room, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Squash courts, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Track, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Trophy room (Box 2, Folder 15 - 17)
    - Weight room (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Whitney Collection of Sporting Art (now in the Art Gallery) (Box 2, Folder 19 - 20)
  - Architect's drawing, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Elevations (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Floor plans (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Proposed panel for mural, no date (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Oversize and Slides, Series III
  - Oversize
    - Exteriors (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Interiors (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Slides (Box 4)